(信号:Ichibanboshi，男，身高1.8米，20岁。东市镇裁判官办事处)
(Signalment: Ichibanboshi, Male, 1.8 meters tall, in 20s. by East Town Magistrate Office)
爸爸!
Dad!
你粗鲁的混蛋!
You rude bastard!
对不起，我要砍了你。
Sorry but I'll slash you.
什么……
What...
嘿，你知道戴这种面具的武士吗?
Hey, do you know the samurais wearing this kind of mask?
你这个混蛋。
You bastard.
你从哪儿弄来的?
Where did you get that?
看来我终于找到你了。
It seems I finally found you.
哈!
Huh!
你到底是谁?
Who the hell are you?
一坂博，武士杀手。
Ichibanboshi, the samurai killer.
我来了!
Here I come!
(日本武士杀手一坂博)
(Ichibanboshi, the samurai killer)
你的生活…
Your life...
将奉献给我们的国家!
Will be dedicated to our country!
“我们的国家”什么?
What "our country"?
都怪你们这些混蛋
All is blamed on you bastards,
现在大家都糊涂了!
everyone is confused now!
你被捕了!
(Police) You are under arrest!
(警察)不要动!
(Police) Don't move!
该死的!让我走!
Damn! Let me go!
早在我出生之前，
Long before I was born,
某个来自某个地方的人把这个世界搞得一团糟。
someone from somewhere made this world into a total shit.
在这个糟糕的世界里，
In this shitty world,
到处都臭得像屎，到处都是屎。
everywhere always stinks like shit and filled with shit.
因此，武士就是武士，农民就是农民。
Therefore, samurais are samurais, peasants are peasants.
那些悲惨的，只是悲惨地死去。
Those miserable, just die miserably.
这一定是个玩笑。我在哪儿?
This must be a joke. Where am I?
看来我的心脏还在跳。
Well, it seems my heart is still beating.
我们能在冥河吗?
Could we be at the Styx?
到底!我们像鱼一样被捆住了!
What the heck! We are tied up like a fish!
嗯?
Huh?
谁……
Who...
是吗?
Are you?
我是新团八队的队长
I am the captain of team 8 of Shinsengumi
(新圣团8队队长，东藤平介)原名Mibu Roshigumi，
(Captain of Team 8 of Shinsengumi, Todo Heisuke) formerly called Mibu Roshigumi,
Todo Heisuke。
Todo Heisuke.
那个该死的新宫武士?
Huh, the shit samurai from Shinsengumi?
你没有资格鄙视一个武士，一坨屎。
There is no qualification to despise a samurai for you, a sack full of shit.
突然什么…
Suddenly what...
那个混蛋好像从他嘴里吐了些蛆。
The shit sack seems to have spit some maggots from his mouth.
你为什么带我们来这里?
Why did you take us here?
快速地把它说清楚。
Make it clear quickly.
你要杀了我们这些本该被砍头的人吗?
Are you going to kill us who were supposed to be beheaded?
在8月18日的政治变革中，
In the political change on August 18th,
新团的高管们
the executives of Shinsengumi,
包括近藤Isami导演，都被人暗杀了。
including Director Kondo Isami, were all assassinated by someone.
导演!Hijikata !
Director! Hijikata!
每个人都…
Everyone...
你们今天都被判了死刑。
You all were sentenced to death today.
所以你们都死了，然后复活成为新团的高管。
So you all died and resurrected as Shinsengumi executives.
你是说，像个政治诱饵?
You mean, like a political decoy?
因为真实的那个人已经死了，
As the authentic person has died already,
是吗?
Eh?
“替代品”不是更准确吗?
Isn't "a substitute" more accurate?
作为替代品，
Acting as the substitutes,
如果新统能坚持下去
if Shinsengumi can keep on,
你的死刑将被免除。
your death penalty will be written off.
如果你拒绝,
If you refuse,
你知道了这个秘密就不能活下去了。
you can not be kept alive having known the secret.
如果我们拒绝，就会被处死。
Execution as it is if we refuse.
所以你选择了罪犯。
That's why you chose the criminals.
多么不合理的策略……
What an unreasonable strategy...
从一个逆境到另一个逆境……
From one adversity to another...
Isami近藤，Serizawa Kamo，三南圭助，
Kondo Isami, Serizawa Kamo, Sannan Keisuke,
斋藤元，原田佐助，秋田宗司，
Saito Hajime, Harada Sanosuke, Okita Soji,
Nagura Shinpachi Hijikata Toshizo。
Nagura Shinpachi, Hijikata Toshizo.
选择。
Choose.
要么死在这里，要么当替补。
Die here or be a substitute.
shinengumi是做什么的?
What dose Shinsengumi do?
在松平·片森大人的命令下，
Under the order from Lord Matsudaira Katamori,
维护首都公共秩序。
maintain public order of the capital.
我们需要砍人吗?
Do we need to cut somebody down?
是的。
Yes.
我把它。
I take it.
Hijikata中南海,
Hijikata Toshizo,
受欢迎的。
welcome.
你就这样加入了新团?
You just join Shinsengumi like this?
我只擅长砍人。
I'm only good at slashing people.
只要我杀人还能赚钱，作为新团或刺客，
As long as I get paid for killing people, as a Shinsengumi or an assassin,
这是相同的。
it's the same.
(Sakuya暗杀者)
(Sakuya, the assassinator)
到目前为止，作为一名杀手，我遵守了规则，
So far I have followed the rules as an assassin,
作为新圣美的我现在应该遵循什么?
What should I follow now as Shinsengumi?
我。Todo Heisuke是这里的规矩。
Me. Todo Heisuke is the rule here.
明白了。
Got it.
啐!真是个马屁精!
Pfft! What an apple polisher!
我想吃很多!
I want to eat a lot!
当然，你可以吃饱。
Of course, you can eat your fill.
无论是食物还是饮料。
No matter foods or drinks.
我在,新撰组!
I'm in, Shinsengumi!
原田Sanosuke,欢迎你。
Harada Sanosuke, welcome.
哇，我会尽力的!
Wow, I will do my best!
多吃!
And eat a lot!
(Bou，大胃王)
(Bou, the big eater)
事实上，我没有理由拒绝。
There's no reason for me to refuse actually.
我嘉塔罗，也会加入新团。
I, Gyatarou, will also join Shinsengumi.
Nagakura Shinpachi,欢迎你。
Nagakura Shinpachi, welcome.
我不能接受死在这里。
It's unacceptable for me to die here.
我还没喝够酒，
I have not gotten enough with drinks,
(犯罪收集者嘉塔鲁)女人还是赌博!
(Gyatarou, the crime collector) women or gambling!
愚蠢的剑客!
Stupid Shinsengumi!
即使我腐烂了，我也只侍奉陛下。
I serve only His Majesty even if I rot.
我永远不会成为巴库夫的走狗。
I will never be the running dog of Bakufu.
第808届…
The 808th...
我做错了什么吗?
Did I do anything wrong?
不,它很好。
No, it's fine.
我就录下七泽神摩死于意外。
I'll just record that Serizawa Kamo died of accident.
该死的武士，你把人的生命当什么?
Damn samurais, what do you take people's lives as?
哈哈!从某种意义上说，这是一个比监狱更糟糕的地方。
Haha! Here's a even worse place than the prison in a sense.
这可能是一个愚蠢的问题，但是……
This may be a foolish question, but...
我可以拥有这具尸体吗?
Is it okay for me to have this corpse?
无论什么。
Whatever.
那么，我加入了，新统。
Then, I am in, Shinsengumi.
Sannan圭佑,欢迎你。
Sannan Keisuke, welcome.
因为不会缺少受伤的病人
Because there will be no shortage of injured patients
这是人体解剖结构。
and human anatomical bodies here.
(精神病医生索根)
(Sogen, the psycho doctor)
好吧，我也要加入新团。
Well, I will join Shinsengumi too.
齐藤Hajime,欢迎你。
Saito Hajime, welcome.
如果有那么多尸体
If there are so many corpses
为了那些无法安息的灵魂，
for the souls that cannot rest in peace,
总得有人为他们祈祷，对吧?
someone have to pray for them, right?
(堕落的修士苏苏兰)
(Suzuran, the depraved monk)
我有一件事要确认。
I have one thing to confirm.
我真的可以代替秋田宗二吗
Is it really okay for me to be a substitute for Okita Soji
作为一个女人吗?
as a woman?
W…女人?
W...Woman?
新统完全是精英主义。
It's completely meritocratic in Shinsengumi.
这只是你作为女人的问题。
It's only your problem of being a woman.
明白了。我也在。
Got it. I'm also in.
Okita Soji,欢迎你。
Okita Soji, welcome.
为了测试我的潜力，
To test my potential,
我在伪装。
I'm in disguise.
无论是剑术还是知识，
No matter in Kenjutsu or in knowledge,
我不会输给男人!
I won't lose to men!
(Akira，一个伪装成男性的女囚犯)
(Akira, a female prisoner in male disguise)
我从守卫那里听说你曾是剑术教练。
I heard from the guards that you worked as a Kenjutsu instructor.
确实。
Indeed.
我要你训练替补队员。
I want you to train the substitutes.
明白了。
Got it.
然后，只有你离开了。
Then, only you left.
选择。
Choose.
死在这里,
Die here,
或者和我们一起改变历史。
or change the history with us.
我才不要当什么狗屁武士!
I won't be a shit samurai!
我的家人都被他杀死了!
My families were killed by him!
戴着奇怪面具的武士!
The samurai wearing a weird mask!
你的生活…
Your lives...
将奉献给我们的国家!
Will be dedicated to our country!
跑,你所有!
Run, you all!
啊!
Ah!
——爸爸!——亲爱的!
- Dad! - Darling!
Ichibanboshi !
Ichibanboshi!
住在……
Live on...
什么“改变历史”?
What "change the history"?!
你们这些拿着剑的混蛋，无辜的杀人犯怎么敢说这些崇高的废话!
How dare you sword-equipped bastards, murders of innocence say those lofty bullshit!
我最恨武士!
I hate samurais the most!
就是那个武士戴的奇怪面具…
Is the weird mask that samurai wore...
像这样的吗?
like this?
是吗?
Eh?
你从哪儿弄来的…
Where did you get that...
这是杀害新团干部的人的面具。
This is the mask of those who killed the executives of Shinsengumi.
它来自一个叫Zomennooni的组织。
It's from an organization called Zomennooni.
真巧，我们有同样的敌人。
What a coincidence, we have the same enemies.
shinengumi在找Zomennooni。
Shinsengumi is looking for that Zomennooni.
你也找到它们了吗?
Do you also find them too?
是的。
Yes.
新统一定会消灭扎门努尼，为死者报仇。
Shinsengumi will definitely destroy Zomennooni and avenge the dead.
你也想报仇吗?
Do you also want to avenge?
当然!我一定会为我的家人报仇的!
Of course! I will avenge my families for sure!
好!
Good!
这是长曾根·冲进·纽道·高铁。
This is Nagasone Okisato Nyudo Kotetsu.
它现在是近藤Isami导演珍爱的宝剑。
It is now Director Kondo Isami's cherished sword.
你会拿起这把剑，变成近藤Isami吗?
Will you take this sword and become Kondo Isami?
为了报复我的家人，
To take a revenge for my families,
我愿意做任何事!
I will do anything!
甚至成为一个该死的武士!
Even become a shit samurai!
我…
I...
我将……
I will...
成为科多兽Isami !
Become Kodo Isami!
(照!Bakumatsu坏男孩)
(Shine On! Bakumatsu Bad Boys)
(爱祖总部、近开口诀)
(Headquarter of Aizu, Konkaikoumyouji)
(野祖领地领主，松平片森)
(Lord of Aizu Domain, Matsudaira Katamori)
(野祖领地领主，松平片森)Todo，替换计划进行得怎么样了?
(Lord of Aizu Domain, Matsudaira Katamori) How is the substitutes plan going , Todo?
他们今天加入了我们。
They joined us today.
首都的公共秩序一天比一天差。
The public order in the capital is getting worse everyday.
为了不增加不满的浪人的数量，
So as not to increase the number of malcontent ronins,
新统现在不能解散。
Shinsengumi shall not be disbanded now.
这是另一个累人的任务，但是
This is another tiring task but
请照顾和培训他们。
please take care of and train them.
是的!我会严格指导他们。
Yes! I will instruct them strictly.
Chomp的声响。
Chomp, chomp.
来吧，我们已经有这么好的胳膊了，我们应该……
Come on, we already got some decent arm like this, how long should we...
只有白痴才会玩剑。
Only idiots play with a sword.
烦人的!
Annoying!
是吗?
Eh?
那个小男孩去哪儿了?
Where did that little boy go?
东藤去找片森大人。
Todo went for Lord Katamori.
那是谁?
Who is that?
他是御津郡京都的军事特派员。
He is the Military Commissioner of Kyoto from Aizu Domain.
他是我们的主。记住，你这个白痴。
He's our lord. Remember that, you idiot.
你个混蛋，你叫我白痴已经有一段时间了。
You bastard, you've been calling me idiot for a while now.
停止。
Stop.
啊?
Ah?
让我们开始训练。
Let's start training.
Katamori勋爵
Lord Katamori,
(相津域Koyokata, Akizuki Teijiro) [Koyokata:日本幕府时期的官职]
(Aizu Domain Koyokata, Akizuki Teijiro) [Koyokata: An official position in Japan during the Bakufu Time]
(Aizu域顾问，Akizuki Teijiro)与其依赖没有高管的新统，
(Aizu Domain Counsellor, Akizuki Teijiro) Rather than relying on Shinsengumi without executives,
(相津域参赞，秋月泰二郎)Bakufu拥有的Mimawarigumi怎么样?
(Aizu Domain Counsellor, Akizuki Teijiro) how about the Mimawarigumi owned by Bakufu?
秋月，Mimawarigumi不是正在召集追随者吗?
Akizuki, isn't Mimawarigumi right in middle of rallying immediate followers?
我们现在只能依靠新统了。
We can only rely on Shinsengumi now.
这是一个遗憾，但这就是现在日渐衰弱的Bakufu的现状。
It's a shame but that is the actualities of the now languishing Bakufu.
所以，不要太依赖罪犯。
Todo, don't rely too much on the criminals.
这足以让德百叶家族暂时受到惊吓。
It's enough to keep the prestige to scare the Tobakuha for a while.
我非常感激你的好意。
I appreciate your kindness very much.
我一定会恢复新统。
I will definitely restore Shinsengumi.
确保首都的公共秩序…
And secure the public order of the capital...
你们有人学过剑术吗?
Has anyone of you learned about Kenjutsu?
不。
No.
我用这个。
I use this.
I with this.
僧侣们从来没有杀死。
Monks never kill.
火药更有效。
Well, gunpowder is more efficient.
我忍不住担心未来。
I can't help worrying about the future...
新统以诚为旗，汇聚各种身份的人，
Shinsengumi, gathering people with various status, takes Sincerity as the flag,
以武士道为准则
and Bushido as the rule.
因此，剑术不可忽视。
Therefore, Kenjutsu cannot be neglected.
现在让我们来一场Jigeiko的较量。[竖井子:剑道术语，指自由练习]
Now let's have a bout as Jigeiko. [Jigeiko: a Kendo term for free practice]
近藤!
Kondo!
近藤局长。
Director Kondo.
啊,是我。
Ah, it's me.
好吧，我们开始吧!
Okay, let's do it!
不用考虑，放马过来吧。
No consideration, bring it on.
我不用这样的东西。
I don't use such a thing.
那就不是练习了。
Hey, then it won't be a practice.
关键是要赢，对吧?
The thing is to win, right?
赢了!
Win!
我下令调查面具的事。
I ordered investigations about the mask.
它似乎和能乐有关。
It seems to be related to Nogaku.
Nogaku吗?
Nogaku?
如果是稀有的东西，
If it's something rare,
要找到它并不难。
it won't be hard to track it down.
我们也将继续调查。
We will also keep investigating.
我真的很感激。
I really appreciate it sincerely.
待办事项。
Well, Todo.
我听说浪人在岛原和祗园游荡。
I heard that ronins were wandering around in Shimabara and Gion.
我会尽快下令逮捕他。
I will order the arrest as soon as possible.
把木剑捡起来!
Pick up the wooden sword!
我要用我自己的方式战斗!
I will fight in my own way!
我很惊讶他居然用那玩意打架。
I am surprised that he fights with that.
从另一个角度来说，这令人印象深刻。
In another way, that's impressive.
为什么他是近藤导演?
Why is he Director Kondo?
嗯?
Huh?
愚蠢的博世……
Stupid Boshi...
停!
Stop!
你这个笨蛋!
You idiot!
你在干什么!
What are you doing!
你脑子里有浆糊吗，你这个烂面包!
Is there any paste stuck in your brain, you rotten bun!
剑是武士的灵魂。
The sword is the soul of a samurai.
而不是扔在地上的东西!
Not something thrown away on the ground!
我讨厌剑。
I hate swords.
这个烂屌丝太得意忘形了。
The shitty loser have got carried away.
什么!
What!
你应该毫不考虑地打他。
You should have hit him without any consideration.
但是…
But...
我们要对抗的对手不是那些踢就能打败的对手。
The opponents we will fight are not those can be defeated just by kicks.
你有为家人报仇的意愿吗?
Do you even have the will to avenge your family?
我知道。
I know.
一旦我开始练剑术，我就会立刻成为其中的佼佼者。
As soon as I start with Kenjutsu, I will become the best among them immediately.
大家准备好!
Get ready, you all!
第一个作品来了!
Here comes the first work!
从现在开始，在城里巡逻
From now on, patrol the city
逮捕罪犯!
and arrest the criminals!
太棒了!我要砸烂它们!
Great! I will smash them!
粉碎……?
Smash...?
粉碎他们!
Smash them!
有被砸的猎物吗?
Is there any prey for the smashing thing?
当然可以。
Of course.
阿基拉，你以前摔过吗?
Akira, have you ever smashed before?
不，我也从来没有砸过……
No, I have also never smashed...
粉碎……它是德国吗?
Smash... Is it Germany?
谁在乎!这是逮捕行动!
Who cares! This is an arrest op!
以有实际经验者为中心，分为三个小组。
Divide into three teams centered on those with actual experiences.
嘉塔鲁，布和我去祗园。
Gyatarou, Bou and I will go to Gion.
罗杰!
Roger!
Akira, Sogen, Suzuran，你们去Arasuma。
Akira, Sogen, Suzuran, you go to Arasuma.
罗杰!
Roger!
左边的一坂博和佐库……
The left Ichibanboshi and Saku...
嘿!
Hey!
我为什么要和他在一起!
Why do I have to be with him?!
Sakuya，你很坚强。
Sakuya, you are strong.
即使驮着一只小狗到处乱叫乱跑，
Even with a burden puppy yapping and running around,
你还能应付的，对吧?
you still can deal with it, right?
谁是小狗?
Who is a puppy?!
你是狗!
You are the dog!
不仅Ichibanboshi。
Not only Ichibanboshi.
你还不是剑道专家。
You are yet not expert at Kendo.
尽可能避免战斗。明白吗?
Evade fight if possible. Understand?
罗杰!
Roger!
你粗鲁的混蛋!
You rude bastard!
所以弱。
So weak.
是吗?
Eh?
所以弱…
So weak...
我把这把剑给你好吗?
Shall I give you this sword?
拿着它，为国家工作吧……
Take it, and work for the country...
(天妇罗)
(Tempura)
愚蠢的!
Stupid!
这是一个武士应该做的吗?
Is it something a samurai should do?
你……
You...
对不起。
Sorry.
不介意。不介意。
Don't mind. Don't mind.
你惹恼了他。
You annoyed him.
嗯……
Umm...
嘉塔鲁，我们会收到巴库夫的薪水。
Gyatarou, we will receive salaries from Bakufu.
你不需要这么做。
You don't need to do so.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
给它回来了!你不再是罪犯了。
Give it back! You are no loner a criminal.
这是你的钱包吗?
Is this your purse?
是的,谢谢!
Yes, thanks!
明拿剑的时候太酷了!
Akira was so cool with the sword!
即使我必须死，我也想被阿基拉这样的美女杀死。
Even if I have to die, I want to be killed by a beauty like Akira.
你以前不是和尚吗?
Aren't you a monk before?
你可以和女人调情吗?
Is it okay for you to flirt with ladies?
♬看见一个和尚在买竖琴
♪Saw a monk buying a harpin.♪
我就是这样一个和尚。
I am such a monk.
饶了我吧。
Give me a break.
在那里……
There...
待办事项!
Todo!
这是十字路口的杀戮。
It's a crossroads killing.
伤口很浅，但血…
The wound is shallow, but the blood is...
爸爸!
Dad!
这的确是个奇怪的伤口。
It's indeed a strange wound.
我已经,绝望……
I'm already, hopeless...
我会处理的。
I will deal with it.
你存活的几率是93.5%
The chance of your survival is about 93.5%.
或者你想成为人体解剖学的材料?
Or you want to become materials for human anatomy?
别担心。
Don't worry.
如果你死了，这里还有个和尚。
If you die, you have a monk here.
这都是你的责任。
It's all on you here.
让我们去追捕那些心怀不满的浪人。
Let's chase the malcontent ronins.
我会在剑术上追上你的，小菜一碟。
I'll catch up with you in Kenjutsu like a piece of cake.
很快就能成为最好的。
and become the best in no time.
如果你能少一些白痴，你已经是最好的了。
You are already the best if you can be less idiot.
你这个混蛋!
You bastard!
的帮助!
Help!
剑…
That sword...
是我!我是第一个找到它的!
It's me! I'm the first to find it!
嘿!
Hey!
为我们的国家,
For our country,
你的生命将被奉献!
your life will be dedicated!
砸你!
Smash you!
我找到你了，蒙面混蛋!
I found you, masked bastard!
Sakuya，不要妨碍我!
Sakuya, don't hinder me!
闭嘴。
Shut up.
809人……
The 809th person...
该死的!
Damn!
真的有一个白痴突然一头扎进了敌人的怀抱。
There is really an idiot who suddenly plunged into the enemy.
这是没有办法的。我的身体自己移动了。
It can't be helped. My body just moved itself.
先了解你的敌人。稍后再拔剑。
Know your enemy first. Draw your sword later.
如果我们行动迟缓，会有人丧命的!
Someone will be killed if we are slow on it!
你以为你佩剑是干什么的?
What do you think you're wearing a sword for?
砍人。
To cut down people.
我是不同的。我想保护人们。
I am different. I want to protect people.
——等待!-按照指示，我们应该返回…
- Wait there! - As instructed, we should return...
愚蠢的博世。
Stupid Boshi.
待办事项!
Todo!
Sakuya。
Sakuya.
有什么事吗?
What's the matter?
一个心怀不满的浪人出现在岛原。
A malcontent ronin showed up in Shimabara.
他戴着那个奇怪的面具，用着一把奇怪的剑。
He wore that weird mask and used a weird sword.
Ichibanboshi在哪?
Where is Ichibanboshi?
他不服从命令，独自去追赶。
He disobeyed the order and went chasing alone.
,傻瓜!
That fool!
一只无用的屎壳郎!
As a mere useless dung beetle!
我不会让你跑掉的。我不会让你跑掉的。
I won't let you get away. I won't let you get away.
的帮助!
Help!
停止……
Stop...
像我这样的人……
People like me...
已经足够了…
are more than enough...
停止! !
Stop!!!!!!!
Kotetsu……
Kotetsu...
光……
That light is...
早在我出生之前，
Long before I was born,
某个来自某个地方的人把这个世界搞得一团糟。
someone from somewhere made this world into a total shit.
你是谁?
Who are you?
呃,我吗?
Eh, me?
我是……
I am...
我是京都军事特派员的代理人，
I am an agent of the Military Commissioner of Kyoto,
《新魂》的导演，Isami近藤!
the director of Shinsengumi, Kondo Isami!
虽然我只是个刚被任命不久的新人。
Though I'm just a rookie who got appointed not long ago.
这个一直臭得像屎一样的世界现在变了
The world that always stinks like a shit is now
开始改变!
starting to change!
(第一集A方案!罪犯组成的新队形)
(Episode 1 A Scheme! The Shinsengumi Made of Criminals)
(照!Bakumatsu坏男孩!)
(Shine On! Bakumatsu Bad Boys!)
(照!)
(Shine On!)
(照!)为什么"shine on"要读成Bucchigire?
(Shine On!) Why do you pronounce "shine on" as in Bucchigire?
(照!)
(Shine On!)
(照!)这不是巴基吗，
(Shine On!)NIsn't this part Bucchi,
(照!)
(Shine On!)
(Shine On!)这部分是Gire?
(Shine On!) and this part Gire?
我问你这个问题真是太傻了。
I was a fool to have asked you that.
(照!)
(Shine On!)
(照!)是吗?
(Shine On!) Eh?
(照!)
(Shine On!)
(结束)
(The End)